A love story in the city of dreams.
Mulholland Drive is a thriller, drama, mystery film directed by David Lynch.
Blonde Betty Elms has only just arrived in Hollywood to become a movie
star when she meets an enigmatic brunette with amnesia.
Meanwhile, as the two set off to solve the second woman's identity, filmmaker Adam
Kesher runs into ominous trouble while casting his latest project.
Betty Elms / Diane Selwyn, played by Naomi Watts.
Rita / Camilla Rhodes, played by Laura Harring.
Adam, played by Justin Theroux.
Coco, played by Ann Miller.
Joe, played by Mark Pellegrino.
Detective McKnight, played by Robert Forster.
Mulholland Drive is a 2001 surrealist neo-noir mystery
film written and directed by David Lynch.
It follows an aspiring actress (Naomi Watts) who arrives in Los Angeles, where she befriends
a woman (Laura Harring) who is suffering from amnesia after a car accident.
Several other vignettes and characters are shown, including a Hollywood director (Justin
Theroux) who must deal with mafia interference while casting his latest film.
The film was originally conceived as a television pilot for ABC, with
footage shot and edited in 1999 as an open-ended mystery.
After viewing Lynch's cut, however, ABC
executives cancelled the proposed series.
Lynch then secured funding from French production company StudioCanal to repurpose the
footage into a film, for which he wrote an ending and filmed new material.
The resulting film, edited and produced by Lynch's frequent collaborator (and briefly
wife) Mary Sweeney, has left the film's events open to interpretation.
Lynch's refusal to offer an explanation left audiences, critics, and
even the film's own cast to speculate on its meaning.
The film considerably boosted Watts' Hollywood profile and marked the last
feature film role of veteran Hollywood star Ann Miller.
Mulholland Drive received critical acclaim, earning Lynch the Cannes Film Festival Award
for Best Director and a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Director.
It was also a moderate commercial success, grossing
$20.1 million on a budget of $15 million.
It is frequently cited as one of the greatest films of the 21st
century and among the best films of all time.
The 2022 Sight and Sound Greatest Films of All
Time critics' poll ranked it at No.
8, while the director's poll ranked it at No.
The BBC and IndieWire named it the best film of the 21st century, and the LA
Film Critics Association listed it as the best film of the 2000s.
In 2025, The New York Times ranked it at No.
2 on their list of the 100 Best Movies of the 21st Century, while The Ringer
named Watts' performance as the greatest of the 21st century.
The film explores themes of amnesia, loss of sense of
reality, schizophrenia, nightmare, hitman.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.